There is a gentleman – you are a witch doctor.
You need to come out because your situation demands for me to see you.
As we are here, people are waiting in your house to see you.
You are a witch doctor.
Please, come out – Jesus loves you.
After hearing the prophecy from the man of God, Prophet T.B. Joshua, the witch doctor comes forward.
Man of God, I am the witch doctor you were talking about.
- You are a witch doctor?
- Yes, sir.
STANDARD FOR LIFE
After the service, the man of God, Prophet T.B. Joshua prays in the name of Jesus Christ.
The power of the Holy Spirit causes many to fall under the anointing.
When the witch doctor, who received the prophecy comes forward, Prophet T.B. Joshua prays for him,
and every chain that satan used to connect him to himself is broken, putting an end to his past,
and giving birth to his future, in Jesus' name.
TESTIMONY CONTINUES
Emmanuel!
(God With Us – Matthew 1:23)
My name is His Mystical Majesty Dr. Prof. Anayo Umumakwe.
Originally I'm from Imo State but I reside in Enugu State, Nigeria - that is where I stay and practice.
The next person to me is my beautiful and humble wife,
and my third son,
and this is the last boy.
The other two boys are not here.
Can you tell us as a witch doctor...
You introduced yourself as a "Mystical Majesty".
Now, tell us, how you practice this witch doctor's art, and how did it all begin.
My mother told me that I stayed 18 months in the womb.
So, when I was born, they said they went somewhere, because my family has an idol-worshipping background.
There were so many great men before me; they said I was the next high priest.
At the age of 16 I started having hallucinations, I could not stay in the class, I was living in a dormitory.
Sometimes, I left the dormitory and went to sleep in the bush.
Sometimes, I would go and sleep in an uncompleted building.
Something used to tell me; there was something that used to talk to me,
"Go away from here, these people want to kill you".
You mean you used to hear voices at that tender age?
Yes, I used to hear voices.
When my parents got to know this, they said they went somewhere,
and they said that the time for me to start my work has come.
We were living in Abia State, so we went home.
My grandmother and my father were alive then;
they brought a very known herbal doctor, known all over in my area.
He came and performed the rite; they made the shrine for me.
In that shrine a clay-pot was half-buried in the ground, and they used sticks to make the shrine.
A cock was killed, and they said I should put my hand in that clay-pot.
I put my two hands; they used the blood to wash my hands inside that pot.
They put so many things in that pot which I cannot remember now.
They told me that it was my shrine; that whenever I had a problem,
I should come to this place and talk to the ancestors,
and whenever I started doing my work, this was were my powers lay.
Any person that came to me; I should bring anything brought by that person; fowl, goats or cow -
I would bring it to this oracle.
So, I went back to school.
When I went back to school, the conditions became worse, but I managed to finish my secondary school.
When I finished secondary school...
Apart from all these things, I was still very intelligent at school.
My parents wanted me to read law.
I asked my father, "You said that I was a chief priest, a high priest.
What am I going to do at the university? Let me start the work."
He said, "No".
So that spirit was there pushing you to start the work as a priest?
Yes, the spirit started directing me.
Some people, to whom I wasn't introduced to, would even come to me saying they were sick.
They would say that there was somebody who told them that I had powers and that I should heal them.
I was going to the bush to bring leaves, then I would put them together, and the people would say they're OK.
Other people would come.
So, I believed that that was my calling.
I refused to go to the university.
I was very intelligent; my father wanted me to read law.
I said, "No".
I ran away from house - that was what the spirit told me.
So, because of this witch doctor practice or calling, that you believed you received,
you were unable to go further in your education, to the university?
Yes.
But initially, when you started, you introduced yourself as a "Professor Doctor"...
No, His Mystical Majesty!
"His Mystical Majesty",
and Professor Doctor...
Yeah, Doctor Professor.
How did you come about this, sir?
Anayo Umumakwe & Family
Former Mystical Arts Practitioner
Prophecy Testimony
No, these things, they came spontaneously.
At any stage, they would tell me what to do, what to say.
What really happened was - that when I left the house, I ran to Owerri and entered the police.
My parents didn't know where I was.
I was about 3-4 months in the training school.
My father eventually found me; I don't know how they managed to find me in the police college.
My father went to the commandant and reported that I was his son, and he wanted to go home with me,
that they had made arrangements for me to enter the university.
Then the commandant asked my father to bring me inside the office.
He asked me, "Young man, do you really like police work?"
I said, "Yes, I want to do police work."
Then he begged my father to leave me; that maybe this was my calling.
My father went away.
When I finished the training, I was supposed to come to Lagos.
I don't know who told them that I was a native doctor.
In the night, when convulsions got the children of our officers, they would come and wake me in the night,
saying that they heard that I was a native doctor, and I would treat that person.
My fellow recruits, when they were sick, would come to me and tell me that they heard that I was a native doctor.
I would just enter the bush and bring 1 or 2 leaves, which I don't even know.
Sometimes, I would squeeze it and give it to them to drink.
After that, they would be well.
People would continue to come more and more.
I left the police and went to a village; there is a village in the east,
which is known for traditional healing and 419, and all dubious characters.
I went to the village with my wife.
By then, I only had one son and the second one was in the womb.
We lived there for some time.
Then, I graduated, I learnt.
People were saying, "You are very powerful. Any person you give medicine gets healed.
Why don't you do like this; so that you get big money from people?"
Eventually, the federal government invaded that village because of too much atrocities.
Then, I ran away with my wife and my son; we went back to Aba, where we were living.
I continued to practise this thing.
Eventually, the goverment of Abia State started wiping other states with these Bakassi boys.
I felt that maybe they would come after me, because by then I had touched too many people's lives.
OK, so that place you visited,; where there are witch doctors, who are also into 419 and others;
tell us what are the things you learnt there, and what are the things you began to practise.
They taught me how to "wash money", how to "speak as a spirit", so people would believe that the spirit is talking.
Before then I hadn't known those things, so I combined it with my own, natural knowledge.
Was there anything like "washing money"?
No! Actually there is nothing like "washing money";
all those things are devil's ways of tricking and cheating people.
Money is only printed by a central bank; you cannot wash or invoke money.
They taught me how to do these invocations and how to "wash money".
I left that place and went to Enugu when they started ransacking the area.
I went with my wife; by then the other child had been born - we went to Enugu.
When we went to Enugu, I started practising these things again; by then I started to sell drugs, Indian hemp.
People were coming to buy Indian hemp and with other problems.
Eventually, at that time, I started selling even the cocaine and I smoked...
I smoked to an extent that my wife got worried, we were always quarrelling.
She was asking, "When will you leave this thing? This thing has destroyed many lives."
Often, police would come to the house, raid our house, see my wife's jewellery and money
because she had a provisional store, where she was selling.
They would steal her money and jewellery, they would say that this was "drug money".
Most of the times, they would put me in detention, where only my wife would visit me.
By then, I didn't have any relations, where I could take refuge.
It was my wife who came to the police to bail me.
After some time, she got tired.
She told me that if I didn't stop this business, I would go to prison.
I considered that aspect and I left drugs business, but I was still doing this "herbal business".
When I went to the river, I would make invocations.
There are certain foods that fish like; when you throw this thing into the water, water will make a very big noise,
because all the fish would come to eat that thing.
Then you tell them that the mermaid has come out.
OK.
To get you clear; you mean - when people come to you to do some job for them...
What are the problems they would complain about, before you take them to the river,
to make all those sacrifices?
Some complain of barrenness, of bad business, some other problems -
maybe sudden death in the family, hatred, and other problems.
I would take them to the river, telling them that it was a river mermaid that would solve this problem.
So, you used to tell them that you have a river mermaid that would solve their problem?
Yes.
How do you get the attention of the river mermaid, what are the tricks you used to deceive the people?
You know this "macaroni", or the other long one?
You soak it in water; fish like worms...
When you soak it in water, you will take it to the river.
The moment you put it inside the river, the river will make a very big noise,
because all the fish will come to eat it.
You tell them that the mermaid has come.
They would be behind me; then, I would change my voice...
So, you mean your clients would stand behind you?
They would stand behind me.
You would be facing...?
I would be facing the river.
OK.
Then, after doint that, I would take both my hands up and say, "Remember, that you promised me
that whenever I come to you, you would answer me. Come now and answer me.
I brought Mr. "so and so" for "so and so" problem, and he wants the problem to be solved."
Who were you speaking to, or who were you pretending to be speaking to?
I was speaking to the mermaid that has come out now, as a result of...
Anayo Umumakwe & Family
Former Mystical Arts Practitioner
Prophecy Testimony
Amen.
OK.
You mean, at the time you got there with your client, your client was standing behind you,
and you were facing the river, after throwing that "macaroni" or "spaghetti" into the water,
all the fish would gather to eat, you would tell them, "Oh, the mermaid has come!"?
Yes.
By the time you spoke all those things, you would make them believe that you were talking to the mermaid?
OK, continue from there.
If the person was very far behind me, I could use my hand and to put it in my nose,
"Ahhh...
Professor, why have you come to this place to disturb me?"
I would say, "My lord, it is because of the problem of this Mr "so and so" - that's why we are here."
Anayo Umumakwe & Family
Former Mystical Arts Practitioner
Prophecy Testimony
"Why have you come to disturb me? Don't you know that I'm wrestling with my children?"
I would say, "My mother, don't be annoyed. You know that other people I brought the other day,
they brought goods after. Please, heal them."
Then I would call the client, "Did you hear what the mermaid was saying?"
He would say, "Yes".
"OK. Now, you will be healed."
I would say, "Mermaid said that you need to bring a goat, this and that, including money, 20, 30 or 40 thousand."
Everything would be brought into the river.
When the client goes...
Sometimes, he would be with the money - we check everything -
and that money would be thrown inside the water.
The money that they brought...
Sometimes, you charged them money, they would bring the money.
You used to charge your clients some money?
The mermaid would charge them, "That was what the mermaid said; that I'm..."
Anayo Umumakwe & Family
Former Mystical Arts Practitioner
Prophecy Testimony
So, what the mermaid said was what I would tell them,
but the mermaid did not say anything - you know that I'm the...
When they brought the money, I would first of all...
Because I had a place I used to stay and do this work - it was under three mango trees.
There is a very big shelter.
I would ask them to buy a white handkerchief.
When they bought the handkerchief, I would first of all tie his or her own money,
so that I would know the volume.
Then, I would enter inside the house and cut paper to the size of that money.
Then, I would tight it to the size of that money.
I have a bag that I used - I call it "my magical bag".
The bag has many "compartments" at the front and back.
That money would be in one "compartment", and the fake one in another "compartment".
When we got to the river, I would bring that... because it was already tied -
he didn't know if it was his money or not.
When men were looking at it, nobody would not know the difference between the two handkerchiefs?
No no no, it was a white handkerchief.
But you would know the one that was containing the real and the other the fake money?
- Yes.
- OK.
I would bring that fake one and ask the person to turn it around his head,
and to tell the mermaid to solve his problems.
The person would throw this thing.
He would believe that the money has been given to the mermaid.
Meanwhile, the real money was where?
It was in my pocket; it was my money now.
Anayo Umumakwe & Family
Former Mystical Arts Practitioner
Prophecy Testimony
So, what happened after that?
Then, we would go home...
No, before you went home, apart from taking the money, did the mermaid request any other thing
or did you request any other thing from your clients?
Sometimes, the clients would bath in the river.
After some incantations, I would ask the client to bath.
When he bathed, we would collect the water; he would be using it to bath at home.
Then we would get back to the temple, the shrine.
When we got back to the shrine, I would prepare medicines that maybe kills that illness.
The drugs I know kills that illness - I would prepare and give it to him or her, and she would go with it.
You mean orthodox medicines?
Yes, orthodox medicines.
Not your herbal medicines now?
At the time, I went to the chemist, I learnt how to sell English drugs.
Sometimes, if it was an English medicine that would take care of the illness easily,
I would use the English medicine, but if it was the traditional one, I would give the traditional one.
OK.
Had there been a time when people came to you and complained about spiritual attacks
or poison in their bodies?
What kind of treatment did you give to them?
Actually, some people would say there was something moving in their bodies,
and some people would have swollen legs or hands.
When they came to me, I would tell them that there was something inside, moving in their body.
I had a wire and a cutter; I cut small pieces of it,
depending on the quantity I wanted to bring out of your body.
Then, I went inside the bush and put it in the leaves there.
I would just carefully stuff them.
- Into the leaves?
- Leaves!
Then I would ask you to come with me into the bush and bring these leaves out.
When we got there, I would carefully remove those ones.
You went to the very tree, where you had inserted those...?
Yes, exactly.
Then I collected the leaves and asked you to bring more; you brought more that I would add to the first ones.
When we got to the temple, I would put water in a bowl, I would move those leaves around your body,
and eventually squeeze it.
I would ask you to put your hand and bring out those wires; I would tell you that I removed all of them.
Then I would give him a medicine for swelling.
If it was rheumatism, I would give him a medicine for rheumatism.
If I wanted to give him an English medicine, I would deface it;
he would not know that it was an English medicine.
So, you were practising both witch doctor and doctor together?
Yes, exactly.
Did you go for any training as a doctor?
No no no, no formal training; all these things are allusion; they just come naturally.
Nobody taught me all those things I'm telling you about, now.
OK. How else did you deceive people, and how else did these things affect your life negatively?
This thing has...
I have touched lives of so many people negatively - it distorted my life.
I'm a human being, I have conscience.
At the time, the thing started disturbing my conscience.
I was looking for a way out.
I even tried to destroy some of the things by myself, but still...
I came to know this Emmanuel TV, and I saw...
OK, before you talk about how you came about to know Emmanuel TV,
tell us what happened when you made these charms for people, or these medicines you gave to them,
and they didn't work, and they came back to you.
How did you handle it?
Well, I would change it to another form.
Some of them made problem and went; they just talked because they were afraid of me.
So, even when it didn't work for them, they were afraid to come and confront you sometimes?
Sometimes they confronted me but they would go; they would not do anything because...
Don't you know what it means to take somebody to the river and bring out the mermaid?
They believed that I was a small god, they didn't...
OK.
So, how did you come about Emmanuel TV?
It was my son; they came home and told me, "Daddy, there is a channel.
There is a man of God who is doing wonders. He is healing people.
Please, put this in our house so we could watch it."
We bought this "myTV" which is "strong" and we installed it in our house.
We started watching it.
Then my faith started...
I started regretting some of the things I did.
I saw the man of God delivering so many people; even people who were more powerful,
who did the real thing, who were more powerful than me, and they were delivered.
You mean witch doctors, like yourself, and those stronger and more powerful than you?
More powerful; like that Iguedo - something like that.
The day he came, he quenched the light, which I cannot do, and he was delivered.
I said, "I will come to this place to get delivered".
I continued watching Emmanuel TV.
From there, I made up my mind to come to Emmanuel TV.
Last Sunday, I came with a friend to this place, and the man of God located me.
When the prophecy was given, I said, "How did this man know that I was in this place?
How am I going to come out? Many of my clients will see me, that I'm a witch doctor."
What did you hear the man of God said to you?
The man of God said, "There is a man here".
He was pointing at my direction.
"There is a man here; he is a witch doctor. You need to be delivered. Come out."
I didn't know how to come out; it was when we were standing up.
Eventually, my leg started moving like this...
I was shaking like this.
Eventually, when I put my left leg, then this one followed; I came out.
Anayo Umumakwe & Family
Former Mystical Arts Practitioner
Prophecy Testimony
Amen.
You mean when the man of God gave that message of prophecy that there was a witch doctor here
and he should come out, before you were disgraced.
You knew the prophecy was speaking directly to you?
The prophecy hit my heart, as if there was a blow - boom in my heart, here.
I said, "How did this man know that I was inside that church today?"
I felt I was going to be disgraced.
I said, "After all, this is an opportunity I've been looking for, for a very long time. Go out!"
Then, my leg started doing like this...
Who was pushing you?
I don't know - nobody!
So, just like this - my leg started doing like this.
I managed to step forward with my left leg.
When I stepped out with the left leg, the right one followed - I started coming out.
That was how you found yourself at the front of the altar?
Yes, yes, yes.
When the man of God prayed for you to deliver you, tell us - what was your experience.
When the man of God prayed for me that evening...
You know, I was a chain smoker; I smoked cigarettes, I could spend 1000 Naira on Indian hemp - it was nothing.
Even in my hotel room, where I was staying, I was smoking.
The moment the man of God prayed for me...
He hit my head; it looked as if something went out of my body.
He hit my chest; in the place he hit me here, it pained me as if it was a bullet.
It continued to pain me until I went to my hotel room to sleep.
When I woke up in the morning, I found out that there was no urge; I had forgotten the taste of smoking,
I didn't know how it used to be in my body.
Since then till now, I don't smoke any more.
Anayo Umumakwe & Family
Former Mystical Arts Practitioner
Prophecy Testimony
All those tricks and knowledge you had about witch doctor's job, do you still remember all those things?
I'm no more interested.
Your mind is not even going there any more?
Even in the church here, now; some of my clients were calling me; so I switched off my phone.
They were complaining of one problem or another.
You mean that at that time when you were doing this job, a lot of people knew you?
Many people, people came from far away; you know Enugu -
people came from Port Harcourt, even from Lagos.
OK, so tell us, as you were practising as a witch doctor, how did this thing affect your family?
It affected my family adversely.
Most of the money I got, I used it for drugs, I didn't do anything with it.
When money was needed, I could not bring it.
I brought money when I had it, not when it was needed.
As a family man, you should continue providing every day.
Sometimes they would ask me and were surprised because of the money that was coming in.
My wife would be surpised and ask me, "What do you do with this money?"
I would say, "Why are you asking me what do I do with money? Don't ask me what I do with money.
I'm using it to keep the family up."
Another way, in which it affected my life was that people around hated me for nothing.
Anybody who was sick, they would say I was the person...
They saw me as a semi-god.
They said that I was the person who had bewitched that person.
If somebody died in the vicinity, they would say that I was the person; some even openly.
So many people are not talking to me now; they said that I was the cause
of what had happened to their leg, whilst I was not the cause.
OK.
So now, you can see that it was the demons that were working with you
and turning all these things against you.
Yes, it was the demons.
I used to see a demon in my dreams sometimes.
It would be telling me, "You have to wake up. You are not doing this work we assigned to you.
You don't give us enough animals; we need enough animal blood."
OK, so you mean that for all these years you practised as a witch doctor, you cannot give account
of what you have used the money to do; no house, no car, nothing?
No, no, no; I have used about 2 or 3 cars, but none of them...
I don't know how...
Even if the car got spoiled, I would park it and it would just decay - I would sell it as a scrap.
And today?
I have one even now, that is parked.
We thank God Almighty for your life, for your wonderful deliverance.
Before we get back to you, to listen to your word of advice,
we would like to listen to your wife and children - their own side of the story.
Good Morning, Church.
My name is Mrs Rosalyn Umumakwe.
The man beside me is my husband.
The two children there are my children.
Praise the Lord.
The prophecy that the man of God gave my husband last Sunday was 101 percent true;
my husband was a witch doctor.
It all started when I entered into a relationship with him.
Being a novice in all this, I didn't know about it.
In a short time, I started to see funny, funny things.
I began to ask him questions about all this.
He would buy incense of all kinds, different types of scents.
He would buy different types of coloured candles - big, tiny, small.
I would ask him, "What is all this?"
I would tell him that I was afraid of all this, "What do you mean by all this?"
He would tell me, "Shut up your mouth; I'm praying with all this."
I would say, "OK".
A short time after that, the demon pushed him into selling Indian hemp.
He would smoke as a chain smoker, he would smoke cocaine, he would do all sorts of things,
he would pick offence at every little thing; he was always annoyed.
I said, "My God. Is this the type of relationship I have entered?"
I would console myself.
One morning, I called him saying, "My husband, come, let us pray."
He would say, "Don't disturb me."
It affected us in a very bad way, because some people would come back and tell him,
"See. What you did for others did not work for us"; 419, selling hemp and other things were part of it.
Police would come and beat me and my children up, they would steal my money, scatter the house,
put the house upside down; I would cry.
They would leave.
The case continued like that, until one day, I caught his attention and asked him to sit down.
I told him, "Look in my eyes."
He looked at me.
I told him, "If you try this business again, I will leave you and you will go to jail."
He ran away from that one.
How do you feel now, that your husband is now delivered, after the prophecy?
I'm very very happy, I have peace and joy in my heart,
that God of Senior Prophet T.B. Joshua has arrested him, in Jesus' name.
- Amen!
- Emmanuel!
Let us clap for Jesus Christ!
Anayo Umumakwe & Family
Former Mystical Arts Practitioner
Prophecy Testimony
Thank you, madam.
Emmanuel!
(God With Us – Matthew 1:23)
My name is Master Umumakwe, the man beside me is father.
The woman beside him is my mother, and that's my younger brother.
I have two elder brothers but they are not here; they are in school.
The older one is in Canada doing nursing and nursing sciences.
The other one is in the university of Nigeria, Nsukka, doing medicine.
And I will enter this year, by God's grace.
The prophecy is very correct and accurate.
You mean you have 2 elder ones; one of them is in the University of Nigeria, Nsukka, studying medicine,
and the other one is in which country?
Canada.
Studying what?
Nursing and nursing sciences.
And you?
I'm an aspirant of the University of Nigeria, Nsukka, for pharmaceutical science.
You are also working towards your admission?
Yes.
You mean, you - the children have very brilliant performance?
Yes, we have a very brilliant performance.
Tell us about that.
You mean that what he was practising did not affect you people?
No, it didn't affect us in our intelligence, in our family.
He himself is a very intelligent man.
I used to see his results from the secondary school; he is a very intelligent man.
Anayo Umumakwe & Family
Former Mystical Arts Practitioner
Prophecy Testimony
When I was born into the family, my father was engaged in this native, witch doctor thing, to be precise.
He did it day and night, he never departed from it, till last Sunday, when the man of God prophesied to him.
When I saw some of all this rubbish in his life, I asked him, "What are all these things?"
He would be like, "I'm working with them".
He would buy incense of different colours, candles of different shapes and sizes.
He would see a candle that looks like a fish, I had never seen one like that, and he would buy it.
He would light it up.
In the night he would be disturbing us with some incantations that are not real; all of them are fake.
Sometimes, I would call him as a man, as I've grown up, I would call him, "Leave this thing you are doing.
All the small small boys would be doing this and you will join them."
And he is a "rope smoker"; not chain, because chain has some gaps - he was a "rope smoker".
He didn't even give gaps in smoking, at all.
He could be smoking Indian hemp with this hand, and be smoking a cigarette with the other hand.
He smoked day and night, every hour of the day he smoked and he drank.
He would be drinking and smoking with some of my class mates - boys.
If I met them, I would beat them very well, and he would be smoking with them.
When I came to school, I could not even talk in the class; if I talked, they would say, "Shut up.
Your father is a smoker, he is a native doctor."
I would just melt like an ice-block, I could not talk at all.
In my family, we are very brilliant people.
Sometimes, I would come first in my class
and they would say that my father had prepared a charm for me,
to be the first person in the class.
That made me...
Sometimes, I ran away from the first position; I would miss some exams, miss some quiz,
I would not come to school on time, so that I would miss some classes,
so that my results would not be, as they were if I was punctually in the school.
In that way they would not say that my father had given me any charms to get the first position.
But normally, if I worked accurately, I would have the first position in my class.
But I would abstain from some school activities, so that my results would not be as they would have been.
That made me...
Sometimes, I have the spirit of anger, I can get angry and beat five boys, when they come to face me.
When I was young in my family, my father used to smoke Indian hemp, cigarettes and drank strong alcohol.
The police would come.
He used to sell it also.
Police people would come to our house, even from the drugs enforcement agency.
They would turn everything upside down, steal our money, even my brother's phone,
and the clipper that my mother bought for us - they stole it.
In my family we are all boys.
Sometimes, when they came, they would first of all beat all of us, to make sure we would not attack them.
One "drug officer" hang me up in the air, when I was about 6 years old;
he hang me up, about 7 feet above the ground and he left me there.
I fell down and I broke into pieces; I couldn't even stand up, I broke my hand.
When I grew up, I told my father, "Leave all those small children's something that you are doing."
He would tell me not to disturb him, saying that this money that he has been getting from this thing,
he has been using to train me, ever since I was an embryo in my mother's womb.
So, I could not even talk because he has been the one training me.
He would give me Indian hemp to go and sell it; and I would go.
Sometimes, they would collect Indian hemp from me and they would not give me money.
If I came back home and the money was not complete, he would beat me also.
Those whom I was trying to sell Indian hemp to, would also beat me.
At the age of 4, I started selling Indian hemp.
Sometimes, I would carry it to a hidden place, made of bamboo sticks with a long bench, inside the bush.
I would go there, selling Indian hemp, collecting money.
Sometimes, they would not give me money and beat me up.
They would collect Indian hemp from me and kick me to go home.
Sometimes, I would come back home, telling him that they beat me, and collected the hemp from me.
He would say, "You know those guys that collected the hemp from you. You must go and collect my money.
If you don't collect this money, don't come back to this house."
I would go there, sit down and cry.
Sometimes, somebody would help me, saying, "Come on, my boy; take one coin - go and give to your father,
since they beat you and collected the..."
So all this while...
You mean, as a son, you didn't believe in what your father was practising, as a witch doctor?
I didn't believe him in any way.
I didn't even have trust in him.
What he was doing was totally fake.
Because I used to work with him sometimes; he would give me medicines.
Sometimes, he used to treat people and the people would get well, but the sickness would still come back.
They would come back and be like, "Since this sickness has not gone, return the money",
and we had used the money by then.
They would do some... they would fight.
If they fought, sometimes they would come with police men.
There is a stream behind our house; all of us are boys, we know how to swim - we run.
When we reached that river, we would stand there and be waiting for them.
If they got close enough, we would jump into the water and tell them to come.
They would be afraid because they didn't know how to swim.
We would swim in the river very fast, escaping from someone who wanted to collect 15 Naira from us.
We would swim from there to a very distant place and come out there.
There we would remove our clothes, stay there until they had dried.
We would call people to check if the whole place was calm, before we could come back.
If we didn't make inquiries and come back, the police might be waiting for us in the bush
or near our vicinity and they would catch us.
Every time we used to run.
It has not been easy at all.
So, there has been trouble here and there.
Every day; there was no day there wouldn't be trouble.
If there was no trouble in the house, there was no money for food.
If there was no money for food, there would be a crisis between him and my mother.
Or, when there was no money to pay school fees for my brother, I would come to him, telling him about it.
He would tell me that there was no money.
I have a bike in my area to use as a taxi; I would go to the construction sites and earn some Nairas.
I would come back with the earned money and give to him, saying, "Papa, this is money I worked for.
Must you work as a witch doctor before you get money?
Leave this witch doctor thing, find something to do".
He would be like, "If you tell me that thing again!
It is only satan that can...
God cannot come and answer him, it is only satan that can separate me and you,
if you tell me to leave this witch doctor thing again".
It happened that I used to work as an okada rider (commercial motorcyclist) in my vicinity.
Sometimes, I would get like 2000 - 2500 Naira a day.
I worked as a okada rider (commercial motorcyclist) last December.
I came to him and said, "Papa, my phone is broken and I need to buy another phone.
I'm doing something in school and I need to be online to know the latest news.
I need money to buy a new phone."
He said, "Don't even come closer to me to say it again.
Just stay like 10 metres away from me and be telling me that thing. Don't even come closer."
Sometimes, when he had money, he used to give it to me.
But anytime he didn't have money; if you came to him to ask for money, he would be very aggressive.
He has always been very aggressive?
Anytime he didn't have money, he was very aggressive, but if he had money, he would be friendly,
he would say, "Come and collect 500 Naira, go and relax."
People in our vicinity used to accuse him wrongly.
He himself didn't have the power to kill anybody, to make anybody to have a swollen leg,
or even to do any bad thing to anybody, but with that knowledge that he was a native doctor;
anything that happened - even if somebody hit his leg on a stone, passing near our house,
he would say that my father was guilty of it.
Last Sunday, the man of God prophesied to your father, and he was eventually delivered.
How does this make you feel, as a son?
Last Sunday, I was very happy.
I was glued to Emmanuel TV last Sunday, because I knew he was there.
So, you watched the prophecy?
I watched the prophecy.
I was watching it live on YouTube.
I saw when the prophecy was spoken, and I saw him coming out to confirm it.
I was very happy that he has been arrested, not like he was arrested the other time,
with hands and feet in handcuffs.
Now, it was God that arrested him, and this one is the correct arrest.
Anayo Umumakwe & Family
Former Mystical Arts Practitioner
Prophecy Testimony
Amen!
You mean that every now and then, the police would come, arrest him, put handcuffs on his hands and legs,
but this time around, it was the Holy Spirit that arrested him, and this one is the correct arrest?
This one is the original arrest; not the one they would carry him and put him inside the boot.
There is a mark on my hand here.
The last time they came to arrest him; one "drug officer", he used his gun on my hand,
because I asked him to take it easy with my father
because I could not stay there and watch him beating up my father.
I have this spirit of anger; anytime I see somebody making me angry, I can even... God.
So, since after your father's deliverance, can you tell us the changes you have noticed in your dad?
Yes. He was a chain smoker; he doesn't smoke anymore.
All this incense, candles - we went to the village to capture some of them in the shrine.
We have destroyed it; we just scattered everything because it was only a structure to deceive people.
We burned it; all those things that were shown in the clip - we scattered it and threw it away.
He said that we should leave something for "historical purpose".
I told him, "This one for historical purpose? Don't worry. Go outside and come back.
You will know if you still see this thing inside here."
Thank you. Let us clap for Jesus Christ!
Anayo Umumakwe & Family
Former Mystical Arts Practitioner
Prophecy Testimony
OK, tell us; where is this place, sir.
This is in our home town in Imo State.
Is that the shrine?
Yes, that's the shrine.
As you can see this thing; I'm the person who burnt it down, but we didn't capture the fire.
We just captured this one to show an evidence of him being a witch doctor.
He had a shrine - both at home and abroad.
This one is at home, and there is another one in Enugu.
Any place he went to, he would just sit and look for an item, to make a portable, mobile shrine.
Anayo Umumakwe & Family
Former Mystical Arts Practitioner
Prophecy Testimony
We can see you wearing a red garment.
What does that symbolize as a witch doctor, and what other colours symbolize?
You said you had garments of different colours.
Yes. I have garments of different colours.
This red you see, that is the one I used for invoking spirits.
I have blue, white and green.
I used them for different purposes, as that spirit demanded.
OK.
Can we hear from our brother?
Now, that your father is delivered, and looking at the experience you've passed through,
and today God Almighty has located and liberated this family;
what word of advice do you have for people who are listening all over the world?
My word of advice to youth like me is that they should endeavour to keep calm with their family.
No matter the situation on the ground, they should endeavour to keep calm, because if I didn't keep calm...
There was a time I even decided to run away from home because of all this crisis and trouble.
Every day, there had to be a trouble; even on Sunday, there must be a trouble.
Either we didn't have money to cook food to eat in our house,
or there was trouble between him and one of his clients.
My advice is that you should have patience, keep calm, and endeavour to have patience in your family.
No matter the situation on the ground, you should keep calm and pray to God.
I'm not a praying type, I didn't use to follow my mother to pray in the morning,
but ever since God liberated my family, I have started joining them in prayers, everything.
Anayo Umumakwe & Family
Former Mystical Arts Practitioner
Prophecy Testimony
Thank you.
Because of time, can we listen to the last born of the house?
Emmanuel!
(God With Us – Matthew 1:23)
People of God, Emmanuel!
My name is Meshach.
The man beside me is my father.
The lady beside him is my mother, and my elder brother.
How old are you?
I'm 11 years old.
11.
I have something to say about the native doctor.
About the native doctor: in the night, he would start doing incantations - we would not sleep.
We would not sleep in the night; he would be doing incantations.
We would see a candle like a dog; he would tell you that it is a "dog-candle" that he uses to pray with.
We would see all types of incense, many types of smell.
Every time the police would come to our house and tie his hands and legs.
They would throw him into the car like a ball; he would bounce there.
He did this "orthodox medicine".
When somebody was sick, he would come to our house and tell my father, "I'm sick. I need you to heal me."
Maybe the person was having arthritis in the leg.
My father would bring vitamin C and give to the person to drink.
The day after that, the person would come back to our house.
Anayo Umumakwe & Family
Former Mystical Arts Practitioner
Prophecy Testimony
OK, thank you.
Tell us: you mean when your father gave them charms, medicines - some would still come back?
- Yes.
- For what?
They would come back saying that they were not healed, that the medicine was fake.
What would happen?
They would fight with my father.
Sometimes, they would call the police
and my father would be negatively accused that his drug was not working.
How did this lifestyle of your father affect you in school and in the neighbourhood?
It affected me in the school, because I could not talk in the class.
If I took the first position, because I was intelligent in my class
they would say that my father prepared a charm for me and that was why I took the first position.
Was your father giving any of you charms for school?
No. When it came to that, this thing did not work.
It was just to deceive people.
So, you guys are just naturally intelligent?
Yes, we are just naturally intelligent.
His medicine was just to deceive people, that he was a native doctor.
Sometimes, he would buy a small key and soak it in the paint, and say it is blood...
He would soak the key in the paint?
In a red paint.
And he would make people believe that it was blood?
Blood.
He would use a small rope and tie it with the feather of a hen, and would say that it was medicine,
"Take it, it will protect you."
When the medicine did not work, the people would come back and say,
"This medicine you gave me did not work. Why?"
They would start having problems with my father.
OK. Your father said there was a time he stopped taking this Indian hemp.
Was it true that he actually stopped taking Indian hemp at that time?
I used to see him in the bush, because I normally go to the stream every afternoon.
I will say this in Igbo.
I would see flames of smoke.
OK.
For the benefit of those of us who cannot understand Igbo language - what does that mean?
Where they cook a certain food.
OK.
So, when you got to the bush, sometimes you would see smoke coming out from somewhere,
and you would think that it was a bush that was burning?
Yes. I would go to that place and see my father smoking.
And it would be your father smoking Indian hemp?
Yes.
Then, I would ask him, "Why are you smoking? You convinced my mother that you have stopped smoking.
Why am I seeing you doing this type of act?"
He would say, "Shut up. If you tell your mother, I will beat you up."
So, you didn't like this witch doctor thing your father was doing all these years?
It brought disgrace and shame to our family; we couldn't talk.
If we talked, they would say, "Shut up. Your father is a native doctor."
Since your father got delivered last Sunday, what are the changes you have seen,
and how do you feel as a son?
The changes I have seen in my father's life; because he was a chain smoker before,
but now he is not smoking.
What about the anger?
He is not having the spirit of anger any more.
Before, he used to take offence very easily.
My mother would talk to him, "Why are you smoking?", in a very polite manner
and my father would pick offence.
Sometimes, he would beat my mother.
So now, everything is over; the family is free?
Yes.
Shall we clap for Jesus Christ!
Anayo Umumakwe & Family
Former Mystical Arts Practitioner
Prophecy Testimony
We have heard it all.
So sir, briefly, what advice do you have for people listening to your testimony today?
Thank God; it is over, you have been liberated, and there are many people who are still in this bondage
of deceiving people, having been deceived by satan with fake powers of charms, medicines and whatever.
What advice do you have for such people, who are listening to you now?
Emmanuel!
(God With Us – Matthew 1:23)
My first advice is that people should trust in God.
Anything demon gives to you is not permanent.
Demon has power - true, but God's power is more than demon's power.
People, listen to me: money is not washed or invoked - central bank prints money.
Anybody who tells you that he will wash money for you, or print money for you is deceiving you.
Anywhere you hear a strange voice and they tell you that it is the voice of a spirit - it is fallacy and lies.
Spirits cannot talk; it is a human being that is talking.
Anayo Umumakwe & Family
Former Mystical Arts Practitioner
Prophecy Testimony
So people should not allow themselves to be deceived anymore?
Yes, don't allow yourself to be deceived; it is a fake power.
And those who are still yielding themselves to demons to use as witch doctors, priests and others;
what advice you have for them?
They should think twice before they get into the same problem that I had.
They should think twice - there is no way there at all.
Glory be to God in the highest!
Once again, let's clap for Jesus Christ!
We thank God for everything.
Now that it is over, you have to turn your life over to Jesus;
He is your Lord, Saviour, Redeemer; all power belongs to Him.
Make His Word the standard for your life.
For those who are delivered by Christ's Word must be ruled by His Word.
We pray that God Almighty will give you the inner grace to make the Word of God
the standard for your life, and also for your family.
We believe that soon you are coming back with the deliverance you have received
with greater testimonies of open doors and breakthrough in your life and your family, in Jesus' name!
Amen!
Put your hands together for Jesus!
TESTIMONY CONTINUES
My name is Mr Anayo Umumakwe.
I'm from Imo State originally, but I reside in Enugu State.
This is my humble and supportive wife,
this is my third son,
this is my last born.
The first two children are not here with us.
On Sunday last week, I was in the service, when the man of God prophesied and located me.
He said that there was a witch doctor in this place and he should come out.
The moment he gave that prophecy, something just hit my mind that he was talking to me.
I was sceptical; I didn't want to come out, but at that moment my two legs started shaking.
When I moved my left leg, the right one followed it; so I came out.
That was where my deliverance started.
Since that Sunday, the man of God has been taking care of me; he gave me money
to go and bring my family from the East, from Enugu, and I brought them.
Since then he has been taking care of us - our feeding, our lodging and other logistics.
I'm very grateful to God; I want to thank Him so much for delivering me from this long-lasting problem.
I'm very very happy.
Now, I feel happy and light, I will not go back to it; no condition will take me back to that.
I will no longer do it.
I thank Jesus for my deliverance.
People of God - Emmanuel!
(God With Us - Matthew 1:23)
The prophecy that the man of God gave to my husband is 100% true.
I'm happy.
Since ever he prophesied to him and he was delivered, I'm very very happy.
He has been a changed man and nothing can drag him to that satanic work again.
I thank God for his deliverance.
I thank the man of God for delivering him,
for humbling himself for God to use him to deliver my husband.
I'm happy about it.
Thank You, Jesus.
Thank You, Lord.
My name is Nakwe.
The woman next to me is my mother, and the man is my father.
It happened on Sunday, when the man of God gave him a Word of prophecy
that he was a witch doctor which I confirm to be true.
I'm happy now that he has been delivered.
Ever since he was delivered, he hasn't gone back to any of the characters,
or any of the attributes of a witch doctor again.
He hasn't been smoking since then, and I thank God for his life.
Thank You, Jesus, for delivering my father.
My name is Master Umumakwe.
I'm from Imo State.
I confirm the prophecy to be true; he has been a new man, since he was delivered.
He has not gone back to the bad life he was living before.
Thank You, Jesus, for delivering my father.
My advice goes especially to my partners, those who do the same business I was doing.
I want to advise them that there is no route, no light that way.
There is life, full life in the Lord, Jesus Christ.
They should endeavour to have their own deliverance and live according to the Word of God.
This is my advice to them.
Then, to people: they should not be eager to get money by all means
because what one needs is what people will use to dupe you.
When you are too eager to get anything by all means, that is when you fall into bad people's hands.
That is my advice.
Sir, we thank you for that wonderful advice.
Right now, we would like to present to you a gift from the man of God, Prophet T.B. Joshua.
The man of God would like to give you the sum of 200,000 Naira
to help you to start a new life in Christ Jesus.
Thank You, Jesus.
Also a copy of "The Mirror".
These are teachings from the man of God to help you to maintain your deliverance.
Thank You, Jesus!
Thank You, Lord!
Thank You, Man of God, for helping me, delivering me and supporting me - I thank you.
Thank You, Jesus.
Sir, we want to encourage you that as you start a new life in Christ Jesus,
stay far away from your past, stay far away from sin
so that you can maintain this wonderful blessing, in the mighty name of Jesus Christ.
Amen!
Thank You, Jesus.
Thank You, Lord.
Thank you, Man of God. God bless you.
May God continue to strengthen you - from strength to strength,
more anointing upon anointing, in Jesus Christ's name we pray.
Amen.
Thank You, Lord.
Thank You, Jesus.
TT Robert Begier 12/06/2018
RV: Pavel Tatyana Zheleznyakov 26/07/2018 + Mel